Belén Garcia Martinez

Software developer

About me

A few years ago, I moved to London, not knowing a word of English and having almost no work experience.

Two years later, I was fluent in English and had developed a strong work ethic and a career.

My education in philosophy prepared me to understand complex systems, find problems within them, and solve them by thinking logically and creatively. Becoming bilingual has made it easy for me to learn new languages. While, moving around the world and working in retail have shaped me to be driven, learn fast, work hard, understand people, and be a team player.

But most of all, I just love building stuff

Contact Information

Email belengm.dev@gmail.com

Linkedin

www.linkedin.com/in/93belen

Phone 913-274-0955

GitHub

https://github.com/93Belen

Languages frameworks and technologies

HTML CSS JavaScript Java Python MySQL Jest Thymeleaf

React Redux React Native Bootstrap React-Bootstrap Angular

Unit Testing Figma Github NPM CLI VSC IntelliJ Spring Accessibility

Experience and skills

Javascript frontend frameworks for web applications such as React and Redux Frontend UI libraries and frameworks, such as Bootstrap and React-Bootstrap Performing UX/UI design activities

Build web applications by using responsive HTML/CSS practices

Security frameworks for authorization and authentication

Creating and executing unit testing and debugging

Version control systems such as GitHub

Creation and deployment of APIs

Use third party APIs with Authorization requirements

SQL database

Design and development of full-stack web applications

Efficient data structures and analizes algorithms with BigO notation

Follow accessibility best practices

Production of fully functional applications writing clean code.

Heavily problem solving oriented.

Excellent time managment

Work experience

Whole Foods (Overland Park, KS) Aug 2022 - Present

Sales Assistant

Waiting for work permit

Nov 2021 - Aug 2022 Study Software Development

Deichmann (Almeria, Spain)

Dec 2019 - Nov 2021

Sales Assistant

Online translation services

Apr 2020 - Nov 2021

Apr 2020 - Nov 2021 at Gengo and Rev.com

Whole Foods (London, UK)

Dec 2018 - Oct 2019 Sales Assistant

Aramark (JP. Morgan Building, London)

Apr 2018 - Dec 2018 Catering Assistant

Whole Foods (London, UK)

Oct 2017 - Apr 2018 Sales Assistant

Education

University Of Granada

Philosophy Degree

Spain

LaunchCode Web Development Course:

- Front-end: JavaScript, Angular and TypeScript
- Back-end: Java, Thymeleaf and Spring